haydensmith

Front End Developer

statement

code. I'm highly motivated to design and make products to be proud of and always look to develop my skills and keep up to date with *recent trends*.

I started developing a flash game for school, got an A and I was hooked, designing and developing websites for one the societies, Thanks to this I have proven experience in working on this kind of projects as a team and proven experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript and Bootstrap as well as converting basic HTML websites into WordPress.

I'm an efficiency-minded front-end developer with a passion for pixel-perfect and high-quality

about

Hayden Smith

82 Congleton Road Macclesfield Cheshire SK11 7UW

07450549403

haydenbsmith.co.uk

haydenbsmith @gmail.com

technical skills

Github Atom Bootstrap Wordpress Dev

programming

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript JQuery PHP SCSS

references

Available on request.

personal skills

- Well organised and methodical approach to work.
- Able to analyse complex problems and assess possible solutions.
- · Enthusiastic about improving and a developer.
- · Always keeping up with recent trends.
- · Ensures site made are efficiently coded and optimised

experience

05-09/2015 **Skyzack Digital**

Responsible for working on a range of projects, designing websites and interacting on a daily basis with graphic designers, marketers, social media managers and clients.

- Lead developer for a new website for one of Skyzack's Clients.
- Wrote responsive cross-browser compliant HTML5, CSS, & JavaScript.
- Created and managed Wordpress websites and SEO strategies.
- Participated in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.
- Optimised web assets for optimal speed and performance.
- Introduced Skyzack to 360-degree images as a new service to offer.

2013-2014 Platinum Software, Bangor

Lead Developer

Front End Developer Internship

Lead Project Developer for Android applications. Creating mobile appointment organiser for local businesses.

- · Lead driving force for all programming aspects of the project.
- Ensured projects remained on track for all deadlines.
- Communicated with the business owners to ensure they were happy with the direction the project.
- · Lead final product pitch to an audience of local experts.

2010-2012 **Bangor University Gaming Society / (BUGL)**

Head of Digital

Founding Member and responsible for developing website and all on line presence.

- Saw a gap in societies being offered to used initiative to start one.
- Part of the society's committee (founding member)
- · Created and managed Society website and Social media.

freelance work

The Test tube News

Graphic and Web design

Started off creating website a PSD for comedy news web page,tailored to clients needs. Currently creating a HTML website out of an image in bootstrap. Will then import this all into Wordpress where the theme has lots of antique that can be altered.

settings that can be altered.

2016 Endeavour Gaming

Website Developer and Wordpress Developer.

After Initially being given an HTML template, had to alter it significantly for the specific needs of client and then convert it so it can be used now as a full

Wordpress theme with easy to alter theme settings

Macclesfield
Cheshire
SK11 7UW
education

about

Hayden Smith

82 Congleton Road

07450549403 2010-2014

haydenbsmith.co.uk

haydenbsmith @gmail.com

addation

Diploma in Higher Education, Computer ScienceBangor University, Gwynedd

Modules include

Android and Mobile development.

2008–2010 Advanced Levels Fallibroome Sixth Form College, Macclesfield

Applied Information Technology- B

Business Studies- C Mathematics- D

Open University- How the Universe Works

2008–2010 **Secondary Education**

Fallibroome High School, Macclesfield

GCSE

11 Above C Grade

A Grades in Mathematics, Business studies, Statistics, Science

Diploma in Digital Applications

Merit

interests

- · Skiing (Chill Factor).
- · Socialising with friends.
- · Technology and Gadgets.
- · Design Trends
- Politics

references

Available on request